<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the King. A proclamation declaring His Majesties gratious pleasure touching sundry grants, licences, and commissions, obtained upon untrue surmises.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1625-1649 : Charles I)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 7KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B13167</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99892534</idno>
  <idno type="VID">188205</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2264199627</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">STC 9140</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 21.h.1[51]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide C.21.f.1[6*]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S123441</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99892534</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99892534e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B13167)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 188205)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C10:1[51]; C9:3[7])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the King. A proclamation declaring His Majesties gratious pleasure touching sundry grants, licences, and commissions, obtained upon untrue surmises.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1625-1649 : Charles I)</author>
                  <author>Charles I, King of England, 1600-1649.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>2 sheets (versos blank).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By Robert Barker, printer to the Kings most excellent Majesty: and by the assignes of John Bill,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1639.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Dated at end: ... Yorke, the ninth day of April, in the fifteenth yeer of our reign. 1639.</note>
                  <note>Arms 23; Steele notation: Commissions, whereas 2) A whereof.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Licenses --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:188205:1"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>royal blazon or coat of arms</figDesc>
                  <head>C R</head>
                  <q>HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
                  <q>DIEV ET MON DROIT</q>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>❧ By the King.</head>
            <head>¶ A Proclamation declaring His Majesties gratious pleasure touching sundry Grants, Licences, and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missions, obtained upon untrue surmises.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas divers Grants, Licences, Priviledges, and Commissions,</hi> have been procured from His Majesty, some under His great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> &amp; some others under His privy Seal, Signet, or Signe-Manual, upon pretences that the same would tend to the common good and profit of His Subjects, which since upon experience have been found prejudiciall and inconvenient to His people, contrary to His Majesties gratious intention in granting the same: And whereas also upon like suggestions, there hath been obtained from His Majesty, and the Lords, and others of His Privy Councell, divers Warrants, and Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters of Assistance for the execution of those Grants, Licences, Priviledges, and Commissions, according to His Majesties good intention and meaning therein: For as much as His most excellent Majestie (whose Royall care and providence is ever intentive on the publike good of His people) doth now discern that the particular Grants, Licences, and Commissions hereafter expressed, have been found in consequence far from those grounds and reasons whereupon they were founded, and in their execution have been notoriously abused, He is now pleased of His meer grace and favour to all His loving Subjects (with the advice of His Privy Councell) by His Regall power to publish and declare the severall Commissions and Licences hereafter following, whether the same have passed His great Seal, Privy Seal, Signet, and Signe-Manuall, or any of them, to be from hence utterly void, revoked, and hereby determined; that is to say,</p>
            <p>A Commission touching Cottages and Inmates. A Commission touching Scriveners and Brokers. A Commission for compounding with offendors touching Tobacco. A Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mission for compounding with offendors for transporting of Butter. A Commission for compounding with offendors in the importing or using of Logwood. A Commission to com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pound with Sheriffs, and such as have been Sheriffs, for selling their under-Sheriffs places. A Commission for compounding for destruction of Woods in Iron-works. A Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mission for Concealments and Incroachments within twenty miles of <hi>London.</hi> A Licence to transport Sheep-skins and Lamb-skins. A Commission to take men bound to dresse no Venison, Phesants, or Partridges in Innes, Alehouses, Ordinaries, and Taverns. A Commission touching the licensing of the use of Wine-cask. A Commission for licensing of Brewers. A Licence for the sole transporting of Lamperns. And that all Proclamations, Warrants, or Letters of assistance for putting in execution any of the said Commissions or Licences, be from henceforth declared to be void, determined, and hereby revoked to all in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents and purposes.</p>
            <p>And His Majesty, in like favour and ease of His Subjects, is further pleased to declare His Royall will and pleasure to be, That the particular Grants hereafter mentioned (upon fained suggestions obtained from Him to publike damage) whether the same have passed His Majesties great Seal, Privy Seal, Signet, or Signe-Manuall, or any of them, shall not hereafter be put in execution, <hi>viz.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A Grant for weighing Hay and Straw in <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Westminster,</hi> and three miles compasse. An Office of Register to the Commission for Bankerupts in divers Counties of the Realm. An Office or Grant for gageing of red Herrings. An Office or Grant for the marking of Iron made within the Realm. An Office or Grant for sealing of Bonelace. A Grant for marking and gageing of Butter-cask. A Grant of Priviledge touching Kelp and Sea-weed. A grant for sealing of Linnen-cloth. A Grant for the gathering of Rags. An Office or Grant of Factory for Scottish Merchants. An Office or Grant for searching and sealing of forraign Hops. An Office and Grant for the sealing of Buttons. All Grants of Fines, Penalties, and Forfeitures before Iudgement, granted, or mentioned to be granted, by Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters Patents, Privy Seals, Signet, Signe-Manuall, or otherwise. All Patents for new inventions, not put in practice within three yeers next after the date of the said Grants. And the severall Grants of Incorporation made unto Hatband-makers, Gutstring-makers, Spectacle-makers, Comb-makers, Tobaccopipe-makers, Butchers and Horners. And His Majestie doth further require and command, that there shall be a proceeding against the said Patentees by <hi>Quo warranto,</hi> or <hi>Scire facias,</hi> to recall the said Grants and Patents, unlesse they will voluntarily surrender and yeeld up the same: And also all Proclamations, War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rants, or Letters of Assistance obtained from His Majesty, or the Lords, and others of His Privy Councell for execution thereof, from henceforth utterly to cease and be determined, and are hereby absolutely revoked and recalled.</p>
            <p>And His Majesty doth further expresly charge and command, all and singular the Paten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tees, Grantees, or others any wayes interessed, or claiming under the aforenamed Grants, Licences, or Commissions, or any of them, and their Deputies, that they or any of them do not at any time hereafter presume to put in Vre or Execution any of the said Grants, Commissions, or Licences, or any thing therein contained, or any Proclamations, Warrants, or Letters of Assistance obtained in that behalf, upon pain of His Majesties indignation, and to be proceeded against as contemners of His Majesties Royall commands, whereof He will require a strict account.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Given at Our Mannor at Yorke, </hi>
                  <date>
                     <hi>the ninth day of April, in the fifteenth yeer of Our Reign. 1639.</hi>
                  </date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
            <trailer>❧ <hi>God save the King.</hi>
            </trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Imprinted at London by ROBERT BARKER, Printer to the Kings most Excellent Majesty: And by the Assignes of JOHN BILL. 1639.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>